

Name: Rahman Mousavian

Github Profile: github.com/mousavian

Linkedin Profile: linkedin.com/in/mousavian

E-Mail: <u>mousavian.rahman@gmail.com</u>

Mobile Number: +61 434 177 017

Summary -

By having multiple AWS certifications and +8 years of hands-on experience from OS level operations up to user-facing and edge services, I believe the combination of my passion towards problem-solving and participating in delivering systems that add value to the business can be valuable to your company.

Interests: DevOps, Scalability, Algorithms, and Distributed Systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE.

iflix Platforms Engineer/SRE

Jan 2017 Until now Malaysia & Australia As a part of fast-paced distributed production engineering team at iflix, my main job is divided into two major groups:

- 1. Empowering other engineering team by providing best practices, tools & automating, and enabling cutting edge solution across company.
- 2. Plan, implement and maintain iflix infrastructure in terms of scalability, resiliency and reliability.

Hence my day to day tasks include but not limited to:

- Dealing with AWS services
- OS level operations; (debugging, provisioning, patches, etc)
- Maintaining Kuberntes as our cloud orchestrator
- Metric & monitoring using 3rd parties & internal tools
- CI/CD improvements
- CDN configuration (Akamai & CloudFront)
- Being on-call for infra & core services to manage incidents time to time
- Cost management
- Helping teams to migrate into a consolidated GraphQL+gRPC API from legacy one

University Putra Malaysia

Sep 2013 – Jul 2016 Malaysia

System Engineering Researcher

Under supervision of university professor, I spent 3 years of research to fine-tune OpenStack as the cloud platform to empower a cross-platform dynamic Malware analysis system, enabling it to handle huge requests in short amount of time. End result indicated ~900% improvement on the system in general.

Tools, frameworks, and Technologies: OpenStack, Cuckoo Sandbox, DroidBox, KVM, Python & Java Programming.

Camdy

Software Engineer

Nov 2013 - Aug 2016 Malaysia

As the second employee at Camdy, my job was to take decisions, architect, design and scaffold the foundation of a newly born startup

in technical point of view.

Before I leave Camdy, company was successfully closed seed round funding, gained around 4K active users and business looked on track compared to early days.

I left Camdy to play my "as a team member" card in a fast-paced & bigger company.

Main technologies that I've been directly involved in:

- Python/Django Backend
- Javascript/Nodejs/Expressjs Backend/Frontend
- MongoDB, MySQL Database
- Git, docker, in-house CI Infra

Tiuma

Co-Founder

Jun 2010 - Sep 2013

As a contractor for "Telecommunication of Najafabad (TCN)", we implemented infrastructure including fiber optic, DSLAMs, routers and switches installation, configuration and maintenance and also delivery of DSL lines to end users. (+7K Users)

Haftsin, Rahnema Co. and

Web Developer

JDEIUT 2008 - 2013

Working with various web technologies on projects such as e-commerce and online financial system for different companies.

Iran

Education -

Master's Universiti Putra Malaysia

Dissertation subject: Enhanced Cross-Platform Dynamic Malware

Analysis Using Cloud Computing

Bachelor

Malaysia - 2017

Islamic Azad University

Dissertation subject: Design Patterns in Java

Iran - 2013

Skills __

Programming Python, Nodejs, Go, PHP, Erlang, C++

OS Linux, Windows, OSX

Cloud Platforms & Providers AWS, GCP, OpenStack

Virtualization/Containerization Docker, KVM, Qemu, and VirtualBox

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB

Web Servers & Reverse Proxies Apache, Nginx, traefik

DevOps Tools Various CI/CD tools (BuildKite, Travis, Jenkins, etc)

Automation (Scripting, Ansible, Chef)

Orchestration (Kubernetes)

Logging/Monitoring (NewRelic, DataDog, Grafana, Prometheus, etc)

Certification.

- MongoDB for Python Developers, MongoDB, Inc., 2014.
- AWS Solutions Architect Associate, 2017
- AWS Developer Associate, 2018